American Council for Emigres in the Professions; Records ger017
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
American Council for Émigrés in the Professions Records
1930-1974
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ger017
10 cubic ft.
Chiefly, correspondence, memoranda, resumes, and other materials of the American Council for Émigrés in the Professions (ACEP).
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Series 1: History files, 1941, 1945-1950
Series 2: Annual reports, 1945/1946-1949/1950, 1972/1973-1973/1974
Series 3: Files on individuals
Series 4: Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP
Scope and Contents
The Collection consists of photocopies made of selected files (originals of the complete files were sent to the Immigration History Research Center of the University of Minnesota), and the complete, original files left by Else Staudinger, Director of the Scholars Project in the New School for Social Research, and of ACEP as it was reconsituted 1945-1966.
Historical Note
The American Council for Émigrés in the Professions (ACEP) was founded in 1945. The service was established to aid professional émigrés in their resettlement. ACEP was initially called the American Committee for Refugee Scholars, Writers, and Artists. In 1963 it combined with the National Committee for Resettlement of Foreign Physicians and became the ACEP.
The ACEP gives counseling, as well as English tutoring, to émigrés. ACEP also helps with the interpretation of foreign credentials, job retraining, and placement. People who work in the arts are granted things like art exhibitions, radio broadcasts, and studios for music practice.
The original files in this collection are of more than a thousand "academically trained refugees" from Nazi Germany, as well as from Spain, France, and Italy. Among the prominent academicians are Marc Bloch, Max Ernst, Karl Jaspers, Nikolaus Pevsner, and Franz Schoenberner. Else Maier Staudinger kept the files as director of the Scholars Project of the New School for Social Research, 1940–1945, and of ACEP, as it was reconstituted, 1945–1966.
There are also photocopies of other ACEP records (history files, annual reports, and files on individuals), the originals of which are located at the Immigration History Research Center Archives, University of Minnesota Libraries.
Acquisition Information
Photocopies of selected files from the archives of the American Council for Émigrés in the Professions, acquired 1974.
Original (complete) files located at the Immigration History Research Center Archives, University of Minnesota Libraries. https://www.lib.umn.edu/collections/special/ihrca
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees.; American Council for Emigres in the Professions.; Weigl, Karl, 1881-1949.; Zoff, Otto, 1890-1963.; Broch, Hermann, 1886-1951.; Buch, Babette B.; Ginzburg, Toni Devora.; Redlich, Fritz, 1892-1978.; Richter, Werner, 1888-1969.; Schoenberner, Franz, 1892-1970.; Segler, Gerhart.; Speyer, Wilhelm, 1887-1952.; Ullmann, Ludwig.; Waldinger, Ernst, 1896-1970.
- History files, 1941; 1945-1950; 1
  Scope and Contents
  Photocopies of selected files from the archives of the American Council for Émigrés in the Professions, acquired 1974. Original (complete) files located at the Immigration History Research Center of the University of Minnesota, 826 Berry Street, St. Paul, Minnesota 55101.
  - History files, 1941 (Box 1 (1-History files), Folder 1)
  - History files, 1945 (Box 1 (1-History files), Folder 2)
  - History files, 1946 (Box 1 (1-History files), Folder 3)
  - History files, 1947 (Box 1 (1-History files), Folder 4)
  - History files, 1948 (Box 1 (1-History files), Folder 5)
  - History files, 1949 (Box 1 (1-History files), Folder 6)
  - History files, 1950 (Box 1 (1-History files), Folder 7)
- Annual reports, 1945/1946-1949/1950; 1972/1973-1973/1974; 2
  - Annual report, 1945-1946 (Box 1 (2-Annual reports), Folder 8)
  - Annual report, 1947-1948 (Box 1 (2-Annual reports), Folder 9)
  - Annual report, 1948-1949 (Box 1 (2-Annual reports), Folder 10)
  - Annual report, 1949-1950 (Box 1 (2-Annual reports), Folder 11)
  - Annual report, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (2-Annual reports), Folder 12)
  - Annual report, 1973-1974 (Box 1 (2-Annual reports), Folder 13)
- Files on individuals, Undated; 3; photocopies
  Julius Bab, Horst Baerensprung, Hans Baron, Erna Barschak, Bernard Baruch, Maximilian Beck, George Bernhard, Egon Vitalis Biel, Kurt Bondy, Hermann Borchardt, Wolfgang Born, Max Brauer, Bertolt Brecht, Hermann Broch, Max Brod, Warner F. Brook, Babette B. Buch, Karl and Charlotte Buhler, Josef Bunzel, Ertist Cassirer, Frederick Cohen, Julius Epstein, Toni (Devora) Ginzburg, Francis.Golffing, Friedrich Sally Grosshut, Bernard Guillemin, Ivan Heilbut, Erich von Kahler, Kurt Kersten, Guido Kisch, Alwin Kronacher, Karl Loewith, Jacob Picard, Robert Pick, Fritz Redlich, Werner Richter, Franz Schoenberner, Karl Schueck, Gerhart Seger, Wilhelm Speyer, Ludwig Ullmann, Johannes Urzidil, Veit Valentin, Berthold Viertel, Ernst Waldinger, Karl Weigl, Walter A. Weisskopf, Stefan Wolpe, Otto Zoff.
  - Bab, Julius, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 14)
  - Baerensprung, Horst, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 15)
  - Baron, Hans, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 16)
  - Barschak, Erna, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 17)
  - Baruch, Bernard, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 18)
  - Beck, Maximilian, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 19)
  - Bernhard, George, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 20)
  - Biel, Egon Vitalis, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 21)
  - Bondy, Kurt, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 22)
  - Borchardt, Hermann, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 23)
  - Born, Wolfgang, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 24)
  - Brauer, Max, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 25)
  - Brecht, Bertolt, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 26)
  - Broch, Hermann, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 27)
  - Brod, Max, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 28)
  - Brook, Warner F., Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 29)
  - Buch, Babette B., Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 30)
  - Buhler, Karl and Charlotte, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 31)
  - Bunzel, Josef, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 32)
  - Cassirer, Ernst, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 33)
  - Cohen, Frederick, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 34)
  - Epstein, Julius, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 35)
  - Ginzburg, Toni (Devora), Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 36)
  - Golffing, Francis, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 37)
  - Grosshut, Friedrich Sally, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 38)
  - Guillemin, Bernard, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 39)
  - Heilbut, Ivan, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 40)
  - Kahler, Erich [von], Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 41)
  - Kersten, Kurt, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 42)
  - Kisch, Guido, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 43)
  - Kronacher, Alwin, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 44)
  - Loewith, Karl, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 45)
  - Picard, Jacob, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 46)
  - Pick, Robert, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 47)
  - Redlich, Fritz, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 48)
  - Richter, Werner, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 49)
  - Schoenberner, Franz, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 50)
  - Schueck, Karl, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 51)
  - Seger, Gerhart, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 52)
  - Speyer, Wilhelm, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 53)
  - Ullmann, Ludwig, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 54)
  - Urzidil, Johannes, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 55)
  - Valentin, Veit, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 56)
  - Viertel, Berthold, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 57)
  - Waldinger, Ernst, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 58)
  - Weigl, Karl, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 59)
  - Weisskopf, Walter A., Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 60)
  - Wolpe, Stefan, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 61)
  - Zoff, Otto, Undated (Box 1 (3-Files on individuals), Folder 62)
- Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP, Undated; 4; originals - 1160 individual files
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by name of individual.
  Custodial History
  The files were in the New School for Social Research, in the office of Dr. Saul K. Padover who planned to use the material for a publication. He died before he could carry out this project, and the files were transferred to the State University of New York at Albany.
  - Aaronschein, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 63)
  - Abel, Emil, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 64)
  - Adam, Leonhard, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 65)
  - Aftalion, Albert, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 66)
  - Agafonoff, Valerien, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 67)
  - Aguado, Pedro, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 68)
  - Ahlfors, Lars, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 69)
  - Alexander, Ferdinand, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 70)
  - Algranati, Bruno, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 71)
  - Allers, Rudolf, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 72)
  - Altamira, Y Crevea, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 73)
  - American Commitee for Émigré Scholars, Writers and Artists, 1938-1970
  - Amzalak, Moses, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 74)
  - Ancel, Jacques, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 75)
  - Anignine, Eugene, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 76)
  - Appleton, Paul, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 77)
  - Apt, Max, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 78)
  - Arens, Franz, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 79)
  - Aron, Raymond, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 80)
  - Aronson, Alex, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 81)
  - Arrarte, Prados, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 82)
  - Ascarelli, Tullio, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 83)
  - Aschaffenburg, Gustav, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 84)
  - Aschheim, Selmar, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 85)
  - Ascoli, George, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 86)
  - Asher, Leon, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 87)
  - Auger, P., Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 88)
  - Auspitz, Hedwig, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 89)
  - Bach, Hans, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 90)
  - Bachhofer, Ludwig F., Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 91)
  - Back, Uskar, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 92)
  - Balogh, Elemer, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 93)
  - Baltrusaitis, Jurgis, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 94)
  - Barb, Alphons, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 95)
  - Barth, Karl, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 96)
  - Bayet, Albert, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 97)
  - Barthelemy, Joseph, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 98)
  - Baruzi, Jean, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 99)
  - Basanoff, Vsevolod, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 100)
  - Battailon, Marcel, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 101)
  - Bauch, R., Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 102)
  - Baudin, Louis, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 103)
  - Bauer, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 104)
  - Baum, Iulius, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 105)
  - Bavink, Bernhard, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 106)
  - Bayet, Alfred, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 107)
  - Bayer, Raymond, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 108)
  - Becker, Hans, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 109)
  - Becker, Julius, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 110)
  - Becker, Viktor, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 111)
  - Beer, Arthur, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 112)
  - Beer, Max, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 113)
  - Bekier, Edward, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 114)
  - Belleli, Davide, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 115)
  - Bellido, Jesus M., Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 116)
  - Belorizky, David, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 117)
  - Benda, Julien, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 118)
  - Benedikt, Ernst, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 119)
  - Benichou, Paul, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 120)
  - Benoit, Jean, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 121)
  - Benveniste, Emile, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 122)
  - Berdiaeff, Nicolas, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 123)
  - Berend, Eduard, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 124)
  - Berg, Kurt, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 125)
  - Berger, Gaston, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 126)
  - Berger-Vosendorf, Alfred Victor, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 127)
  - Bergholz, Harry, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 128)
  - Bergmann, Moses, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 129)
  - Bergson, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 130)
  - Berney, Arnold, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 131)
  - Berteaux, Pierre, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 132)
  - Berthelot, Marcel, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 133)
  - Bettelheim, Ernst, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 134)
  - Beuve-Mery, Hubert, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 135)
  - Bidault, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 136)
  - Biedermann, Marcus Meyer, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 137)
  - Biel, Erwin, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 138)
  - Biel, Paul, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 139)
  - Bien, Ernst, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 140)
  - Biermann, F., Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 141)
  - Bing, Rudolf, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 142)
  - Biquard, Pierre, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 143)
  - Birnbaum, Emmanuel, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 144)
  - Birziska, Vaclovas, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 145)
  - Blachowski, Stefan, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 146)
  - Blau, Marietta, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 147)
  - Bloch, Camille, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 148)
  - Bloch, Jules, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 149)
  - Bloch, Marc, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 150)
  - Bloch, Marcel, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 151)
  - Bloch-Laine, Jean Frederic, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 152)
  - Blondel, Maurice, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 153)
  - Bluh, Otto, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 154)
  - Blum, Andre, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 155)
  - Bondy, Otto, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 156)
  - Bonger, William A., Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 157)
  - Bonot, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 158)
  - Borchardt, Adolf, Maria, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 159)
  - Borchardt, Paul, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 160)
  - Borinski, I. F., Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 161)
  - Boris, Gilbert, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 162)
  - Borne, Etienne, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 163)
  - Borowy, Waclaw, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 164)
  - Borsuk, Karl, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 165)
  - Bosch-Gimpera, P., Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 166)
  - Bosse, Käthe, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 167)
  - Boucher, Maurice, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 168)
  - Boulanger, Jacques, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 169)
  - Bourquin, Maurice, Undated (Box 1 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 170)
  - Bousquet, Georges, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 1)
  - Boyazoglu, Alexander J., Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 2)
  - Braun, Felix, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 3)
  - Braunstein, Albert, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 4)
  - Brecher, Leonore, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 5)
  - Breitscheid, Rudolf, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 6)
  - Bremer, Frederic, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 7)
  - Bremer, Hans, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 8)
  - Brendel, Otto, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 9)
  - Bresciani-Turroni, Constantino, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 10)
  - Brill, Erich, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 11)
  - Broch, Hans, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 12)
  - Brock, Werner, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 13)
  - Brodersen, Arvid, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 14)
  - Broendal, Viggo, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 15)
  - Brouckere, Louis de, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 16)
  - Bruck, Eberhard, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 17)
  - Brueck, Hermann, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 18)
  - Brumlik, Joseph, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 19)
  - Brunner, Fritz, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 20)
  - Brunschvicg, Leon, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 21)
  - Budde, C. F. E., Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 22)
  - Burchardt, Fritz, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 23)
  - Butter, Oskar, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 24)
  - Caffi, Andrea, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 25)
  - Cahen, Reinhard, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 26)
  - Cain, Julien, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 27)
  - Calmette, Josephe Louis-Antoine, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 28)
  - Calosso, Umberto, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 29)
  - Camp, Jean, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 30)
  - Candel, Rafael, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 31)
  - Caron, Pierre, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 32)
  - Carre, Jean-Marie, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 33)
  - Cartan, Henri, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 34)
  - Caspari, Wilhelm, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 35)
  - Caspary, Adolf, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 36)
  - Cassou, Jean, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 37)
  - Castelfranco, Paolo, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 38)
  - Castelin, Karel, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 39)
  - Castillejo, Jose, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 40)
  - Cavailles, Jean, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 41)
  - Cazamian, Louis, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 42)
  - Cech, Eduard, Undated (Box 2 (4-Files from Else Staudinger, Director of ACEP), Folder 43)